GALO I. LOPEZ

12235 Creek Turn Drive, Charlotte, NC 28278 | (704) 737-9893 | glopez19@live.com

SUMMARY

Software Engineer with experience in information gathering, planning, design, development, testing, and deployment of custom-made applications in full-stack development. Motivated, dedicated, organized, and goal-driven individual with excellent analytical and communication skills. Apt talent for quickly mastering technology. Self-driven, versatile, and able to maintain a sense of humor under pressure. Skilled at team collaboration while working independently in remote environments.

HIGHLIGHTS

- AGILE/SCRUM Development
- Coding Best Practices
- Efficient Data Management
- API Design and Development

- Debugging and Troubleshooting
- Requirement Gatherings
- Performance and Scalability
- Project Management

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Developer 08/2016 to Current Logical Advantage Charlotte, NC

Developed software solutions for a vast range of companies and industries:

- Developed and maintained console applications that worked as side services for web applications.
 - Learned best practices in design, development, and deployment of web applications and databases.

Software Developer 02/2016 to 08/2016 INSite Business Solutions Fort Mill, SC

Developed and maintained various web services and custom-made applications for a variety of industries:

- Worked closely with BAs to improve UI/UX and functionality, as well as develop new features, of a longmaintained surveying system application using best practices for debugging and troubleshooting in ASP.NET.
- Co-developed a revamped version of the first project that generates complex consumer reports using Angular JS to consume API and SASS front-end framework.

Junior Software Developer Coder Foundry

09/2015 to 12/2015 Charlotte, NC

Intensive, accelerated programming course designed to learn the .NET framework and full-stack development:

- Created a personal portfolio website using C#, MVC5, and JavaScript.
- Created a fully functional bug tracker web application from scratch in MVC, by implementing code first database with user- and role-level security and doing database interaction through LINQ to Entity Framework.
- Created a fully functional web API car finder web application from scratch, by composing dynamic, responsive front-end design using AngularJS, HTML5, and Bootstrap and accessing database through stored procedures.
- Created a fully functional financial portal web application for tracking budget.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Computer EngineeringUniversity of North Carolina at Charlotte

2015

Charlotte, NC

TECHNICAL SKILSS

C#, C++, Java, Entity Framework, ASP.NET, MVC, Bootstrap, Angular JS, JavaScript, JQuery, HTML 5, CSS, SASS, XML, RAZOR, SQL, LINQ, VHDL, C